Girl in the Basement is a thriller, crime, tv movie
film directed by Elisabeth Röhm.
Sara is a teen girl who is looking forward to her 18th birthday
to move away from her controlling father Don.
But before she could even blow out the candles, Don
imprisons her in the basement of their home.
Don, played by Judd Nelson.
Sara, played by Stefanie Scott.
Irene, played by Joely Fisher.
Michael, played by Braxton Bjerken.
Doctor, played by Kim Rosen.
Amy, played by Emily Topper.
Elisabeth Röhm ( "Rame" or  "rem"; German: [ˈʁøːm]; born April 28, 1973)
is an American television and film actress and director.
She is best known for playing Kate Lockley in the television series Angel from 1999 to 2001
and Serena Southerlyn in the television series Law & Order from 2001 to 2005.
She has also appeared in films such as Miss Congeniality 2: Armed and Fabulous (2005), American Hustle (2013), Joy (2015),
Seduced (2016), Once Upon a Time in Venice (2017), The Tribes of Palos Verdes (2017) and Bombshell (2019).
Röhm made her directorial debut with the Lifetime
film Girl in the Basement (2021).
The film explores themes of imprisonment, based on true
story, basement, controlling parent.
The tone is intense.